[
  {
    "question": "To whom is the epigraph to Chapter 1 attributed?",
    "a": "Confucius",
    "b": "Mencius",
    "c": "Laozi",
    "d": "Chuang Tse",
    "e": "Sun Tzu",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which creature opens Chapter 1?",
    "a": "cockroach",
    "b": "horse",
    "c": "dog",
    "d": "octopus",
    "e": "jellyfish",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What causes the main character’s illness at the beginning of Chapter 1?",
    "a": "a cancerous plague",
    "b": "radiation sickness",
    "c": "poor nutrition",
    "d": "excessive alcohol",
    "e": "influenza",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of flower does the main character see?",
    "a": "rose",
    "b": "dandelion",
    "c": "forsythia",
    "d": "cowslip",
    "e": "peony",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the medic say has caused the main character’s illness?",
    "a": "bad food",
    "b": "repressed anger",
    "c": "too much dreaming",
    "d": "a drug overdose",
    "e": "radiation poisoning",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of treatment does the medic recommend for the main character in Chapter 1?",
    "a": "Behavioral Therapy",
    "b": "Surgical Treatment",
    "c": "Voluntary Therapeutic",
    "d": "Radiation Therapy",
    "e": "Medication Therapy",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 1, we learn that the main character’s name is",
    "a": "Henry",
    "b": "Phil",
    "c": "Haber",
    "d": "George",
    "e": "Sam",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Mannie do for the main character in Chapter 1?",
    "a": "soothes him to sleep",
    "b": "covers for his drug use",
    "c": "helps him undress",
    "d": "makes him a meal",
    "e": "calls an ambulance",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Mannie’s occupation?",
    "a": "medic",
    "b": "elevator guard",
    "c": "plumber",
    "d": "janitor",
    "e": "sleep doctor",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What illness does the medic say is afflicting children?",
    "a": "scurvy",
    "b": "kwashiorkor",
    "c": "polio",
    "d": "cancer",
    "e": "diphtheria",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 1, the main character is taking barbiturates and",
    "a": "Concerta",
    "b": "Focalin",
    "c": "Dexedrine",
    "d": "Adderall",
    "e": "Desoxyn",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What nutrient does the medic say that many children are lacking, in Chapter 1?",
    "a": "calcium",
    "b": "vitamin A",
    "c": "magnesium",
    "d": "iron",
    "e": "protein",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What nutrient does the medic give many children?",
    "a": "vitamin C",
    "b": "iodine",
    "c": "folate",
    "d": "potassium",
    "e": "protein",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What question does Mannie ask at the end of Chapter 1?",
    "a": "“What’s that noise?”",
    "b": "“Wouldn’t you like to know?”",
    "c": "“What’d you do with my Pharm Card?”",
    "d": "“Ain’t it great to be alive?”",
    "e": "“Who took my shoes?”",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "The tone of Chapter 1 can BEST be described as",
    "a": "contemplative",
    "b": "nostalgic",
    "c": "hopeful",
    "d": "bleak",
    "e": "wistful",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, what is the referral patient's medical condition?",
    "a": "drug abuse",
    "b": "leprosy",
    "c": "diabetes",
    "d": "cancer",
    "e": "heart disease",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, what is Dr. Haber’s profession?",
    "a": "cardiologist",
    "b": "oncologist",
    "c": "neurologist",
    "d": "pharmacist",
    "e": "oneirologist",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, why did Orr prefer barbiturates over dextroamphetamine?",
    "a": "Barbiturates were more effective at suppressing dreaming.",
    "b": "Barbiturates had a stronger stimulating effect.",
    "c": "Barbiturates have fewer side effects.",
    "d": "Dextroamphetamine had no effect on his sleep.",
    "e": "Dextroamphetamine made him jumpy.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, in The Lathe of Heaven, the sleep doctor uses a dream machine called the Augmentor",
    "a": "Trancap",
    "b": "Hypnagogue",
    "c": "Augmentor",
    "d": "Sleep Enhancer",
    "e": "EEG",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, where does The Lathe of Heaven take place?",
    "a": "Sacramento",
    "b": "Boise",
    "c": "Portland",
    "d": "Denver",
    "e": "Seattle",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, what is the main character's profession?",
    "a": "medic",
    "b": "plumber",
    "c": "lawyer",
    "d": "teacher",
    "e": "draftsman",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, how did George Orr feel about his aunt’s advances?",
    "a": "He was indifferent and distant.",
    "b": "He was surprised and excited.",
    "c": "He was flattered and interested.",
    "d": "He was curious and confused.",
    "e": "He was afraid and resentful.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, how did George Orr’s dream about his aunt affect reality?",
    "a": "It made his mother move out.",
    "b": "It made his aunt die.",
    "c": "It allowed him to speak frankly to his aunt.",
    "d": "It caused his aunt to become a white cat.",
    "e": "It made his aunt no longer exist.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, what does George Orr say about dreams?",
    "a": "frightening",
    "b": "unsocialized",
    "c": "prophetic",
    "d": "exciting",
    "e": "uncanny",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, what does Haber propose to Orr?",
    "a": "to undergo surgery to remove his ability to dream",
    "b": "to try autohypnosis to control his dreams",
    "c": "to take even more drugs to suppress all dreams",
    "d": "to see a different psychiatrist",
    "e": "to dream intentionally under controlled conditions",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, how does the Dream Machine work?",
    "a": "by suppressing certain types of dreams",
    "b": "by playing recordings of healthy brain waves to the subject",
    "c": "by inducing alpha trance in the subject",
    "d": "by analyzing feedback from the subject's brain waves",
    "e": "by sending signals to electrodes implanted in the brain",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, what does Haber use to induce hypnosis?",
    "a": "v-c induction",
    "b": "deep breathing techniques",
    "c": "electronic brain stimulation",
    "d": "autohypnosis",
    "e": "dream-suppressant drugs",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, what does Haber tell Orr to dream about during their first session together?",
    "a": "a car",
    "b": "his aunt",
    "c": "a horse",
    "d": "a cabin",
    "e": "a plague",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, how does Haber react when Orr questions him about the picture in his office?",
    "a": "He laughs and makes a joke about the picture.",
    "b": "He asks Orr to undergo the Augmentor again.",
    "c": "He becomes angry and defensive.",
    "d": "He changes the subject to ask Orr about his dream.",
    "e": "He admits that the pictures has been changed.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 2, what does Orr say about the horse in Haber's mural?",
    "a": "that it looks like Haber",
    "b": "that it is a symbol of psychiatry",
    "c": "that he does not remember it being there",
    "d": "that it has strength and self-realization in animal terms",
    "e": "that it was a mountain before the dream",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  }
]

